Daniel Eaton

34 Egerton Road, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 4DQ (+44) 07565510004 danieleaton15@hotmail.co.uk

dannybongo (Daniel Eaton) (github.com)

Profile Statement

A mechanical design engineer looking to pursue a career in web development. Currently self-teaching front-end development, with a plan to progress onto back-end development.

I am a time served mechanical craft apprentice with over six years of experience in the design, build and implementation of product handling systems for a variety of industries. I am attentive to detail, a keen problem solver and an analytical thinker. My engineering background, coupled with my passion for learning and technology, gives me a strong foundation for pursing a web development career.

Skills

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Linux/Bash
- Git/Github

- Mechanical Design CAD
- Project Management

Experience

05/2021 - Present

Mechanical Design Engineer / Mettler Toledo Safeline

- Mechanical design of conveyors, gravity fed systems, tablet processing machines and slurry processing machines. Industries: food, pharmaceutical, beverage.
- Producing engineering drawings, specifications and risk assessments.
- Leading the 'Triage' team, whose task it is to rectify issues that occur during build and test.
- Increasing departmental efficiency through improving processes, legacy designs and methodologies.

10/2020 - 04/2021

Mechanical Design Engineer / Link Engineering Design

- Mechanical design of conveyors, bogies, turntables and more. Industries included paper, food, beverage and general engineering.
- Liaised with new and existing customers to produce quotations and identify customer requirements.
- Assisted with manufacturing, building and testing. Tasks included: mechanical fitting and assembly, welding and machining.
- Revitalised the company website by adding new content, optimising the website SEO (Search
 engine optimisation) and giving the website a new, modern look. I did this through WordPress. I
 also managed the company social media pages.

08/2018 - 10/2020

Project Design Engineer / KP Industries

- Mechanical design of conveyors, turntables, monorails, lifts, bogies and more. Industries: automotive, nuclear, manufacturing and intralogistics.
- Produced engineering drawings, bills of materials, risk assessments and specifications.
- Project management. Liaised with stakeholders to ensure the successful delivery of a system that meets customer requirements.

09/2016 - 08/2018

Mechanical Design Engineer / Mettler Toldeo Safeline

- Mechanical design of conveyors, gravity fed systems, tablet processing machines and slurry processing machines. Industries: food, pharmaceutical, beverage.
- Produced engineering drawings, bills of materials, risk assessments and specifications.
- Represented the department in the daily board-walk meetings. This involved either resolving issues or feeding information back to the department.

09/2012 - 04/2016

Mechanical Craft Apprentice / Mettler Toldeo Safeline

- Shop floor/manufacturing Worked on every process that goes into manufacturing a metal detector. After this, I moved into system build, wiring and test, where I worked on the product handling systems that metal detectors often work in conjunction with.
- Manufacturing Engineering Assisted with lean manufacturing projects. I primarily worked on a
 project designed to reduce waste during conveyor build. Other duties included writing standard
 operating procedures (SOPs).
- Design Engineering Started modelling basic parts, up-revising drawings and assisting the
 department wherever possible. Eventually, I moved onto larger projects, starting on spares
 orders and then moving onto system design.

Education

- Wigan and Leigh College, Mechanical Engineering, HNC BTEC Level 4 Diploma, Grade: Distinction
- Trafford College, Operations and Maintenance, BTEC Level 3 Diploma, Grade: Double Distinction
- Swinton High School, GCSE, 8 in total, A-C Grade Including Maths, English, Science

References Available on Request